(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-07T22:38:56.103027",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
えー、みなちゃま、
Um, hello everyone!
本日は「轟はじめ生誕祭2024
Thank you so much for coming today to
Rise in motion」に
Todoroki Hajime Birthday Live 2024:
お越しくださいまして、
“Rise in motion”!
誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you all very much!
開演に先立ちまして、
Before the show begins,
皆様にお願いと
I have a few requests
ご案内を申し上げます。
and announcements for everyone.
当配信は一部収録を含みますが、
While this stream includes some pre-recorded parts,
生配信部分もございますので、
there are also live broadcast portions,
いっぱいコメントして盛り上げてください！
so please hype it up with lots of comments!
今もね、じわーって
Even right now, flooding in...
いっぱい「うおー」「こんちくわー」
There's lots of “Whoa!” “Konchikuwa!”
「きちゃー」「パチパチ」と、
“She's here!” and clappings,
ありがとうございます！
thank you so much!
当配信のハッシュタグは、
The hashtag for this stream is
「#轟はじめ生誕祭2024」です！
“#轟はじめ生誕祭2024”!
SNSでたくさんポストしていただけると嬉しいです。
I'd be really happy if you post a lot on social media.
開演中はね、
During the show,
カメラやスマートフォンなどによる写真撮影、大歓迎なので、
taking photos with cameras or smartphones is very welcome,
たくさんポストして盛り上げていただけると幸いです。
so please post a lot and hype things up.
それでは、開演までしばらくお待ちください！
Well then, please wait a moment until the show begins!
えー、みなちゃま、
Um, hello everyone!
本日は「轟はじめ生誕祭2024 Rise in motion」にお越しくださいまして、
Thank you for coming to Todoroki Hajime Birthday Live 2024: “Rise in motion”,
誠にありがとうございます！パート2！
thank you very much! Part 2!
どうですか？なんか、
How's it going? Looks like...
ゴトゴトしてなさそうですね、皆ちゃん。
it's not lagging or stuttering for everyone.
「うおー」って、
Seeing “Whoa!”
「わくわく」「こんちくわ」と、
and “So excited!” “Konchikuwa!”...
だ、大丈夫そうです！
I-It looks all good!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を、
Before the show starts, the requests and announcements for everyone...
ちょっともう一回申し上げます！
I'll go over them one more time!
当配信は一部収録を含みますが、
While this stream includes some pre-recorded parts,
生配信部分もございますので、
there are also live broadcast portions,
いっぱいコメントして盛り上げていただけると嬉しいです！
so I'd be super happy if you comment a lot and hype it up!
じゃあ、パート2来ちゃ！ ありがとう！
Alright, Part 2... Part 2 is here! Thank you!
えー、当配信のハッシュタグは、#おるはしの生誕祭2026 です。
The hashtag for this stream is #OruhashiBirthday2026.
SNSでたくさんポストしてください！
Please post a lot on social media!
えー、開演中は、カメラやスマートフォンなどによる写真撮影、大歓迎です！
During the show, taking photos with cameras or smartphones is very welcome!
たくさんポストして、盛り上げていただけると嬉しいです！
I'd love it if you post a lot and help hype things up!
それでは、開演まで、
And now, until the show begins,
今しばらくお待ちくださーい！
please wait just a little longer!
ワンタイムの脳内命に
In this one-time life inside my brain,
くだらないよ 紛い物だって バリアクター
it's stupid—even if it's just a counterfeit—very actor.
喝采喫しちゃってるようなもん
It's like I'm already tasting applause.
不条理浴びながら僕は這う
Drenched in absurdity, I crawl ahead.
才能はさ どうにかしちまってるけど
My talent might be all messed up, but...
覚醒はもうやってんの
I've already been awakened.
愛にもたれて 狂った心拍数
Leaning on love, with a heart rate gone wild,
生きてく肌 胸は沈んでいく
skin that keeps on living, my heart sinking down.
どうなってんだろうな この鼓動が揺れるの
I wonder what's going on, as this pulse wavers.
あいつなんてもうしょうがねえ
That guy is a lost cause already,
汗水稼ぐお金はどんだけ
how much money does all that sweat earn anyway?
あーだこーだ そんなもんか うるせえ わら
This and that, is that all it is? Shut up, lol.
ワンタイムの脳内命に
In this one-time life inside my brain,
から回ってく脳を満たしてくれ
fill up this mind spinning its wheels.
未来予想図なんか描けない
I can't draw up any vision of the future,
くだらないよ 紛い物だって それ
it's stupid—even if it's just a counterfeit.
あぁ 半端者ならば 叫べない 鳴いちゃう
Ah, if you're half-baked, you can't scream, you'll just cry out.
お互いロンリーになって 僕は思い通り
We've both ended up lonely, and I do as I please.
体温計ですぐまた 罵詈雑言インベーダー
With a thermometer, back again, a foul-mouthed invader.
足が止まってるシューゲイザー 死にそうでもギリですか？
A shoegazer whose feet have stopped, barely hanging on even near death?
のらりくらり躱すわ
I'll dodge around noncommittally.
初めまして神様
Nice to meet you, God.
もし救われるのならば 腹切るわ今から
If I can be saved, I'll cut my stomach open right now.
あぁ get down get down... get down get down
Ah, get down, get down... get down, get down
飲み込んだ好いた悪が 夢を狂わしてんだ
The beloved evil I swallowed is driving my dreams insane.
あぁ 滅多なもんじゃ踊れねぇ 汗水拭いた最後もあっけねぇ
Ah, I can't dance to just anything; wiping sweat and tears, the end is so sudden.
あんな看板 そんなもんさ うるせえ わら
Signs like that, that's all they are. Shut up, lol.
ワンタイムの脳内命に から回ってく脳を...
In this one-time life inside my brain, spinning its wheels...
満たしてくれ
Satisfy me,
未来予想図なんか描けない
I can't even draw a vision of the future.
くだらない世迷言だってそれ
Even if that's just foolish complaining...
半端者ならやれやしない街
In a city where half-hearted people can't make it,
怖がりのままで 僕は甘いと
still scared, thinking I'm too naive...
ええじゃないか
[Ee Janai ka]
パラリラ ここはきっと奈落だ
Pararira, this place is surely the abyss,
声にもならぬ声が
and a voiceless voice
腹の底からせり上がるんだ
surges up from the depths of my gut.
「ダメ！それ！」押し殺す本能
"Stop! Don't!" Repressing my instincts.
ユラユラ 鈍色の海から
Swaying from the slate-gray sea,
幽列車と雲ヶ島
a ghost train and Kumogashima Island.
ただただ 君は呟くんだ
You simply mutter,
「人は怖いね」と
"People are terrifying, aren't they?"
今 弾ける七色
Now bursting in seven colors!
アイアイ アイアイ 宙を舞って踊り散らすの
Aiai, aiai, dancing and scattering midair!
ファッションビートで気取って
Strutting to the fashion beat,
チンケな狂人ぶんじゃない
don't play the cheap lunatic.
報われない悲しみ食らってこう
Let's swallow this unrewarded sorrow!
ファッションビートに染まって
Dyed in the fashion beat,
言うことないなら 息しても無駄だ
if you've nothing to say, even breathing is futile.
アイヤ イヤイヤ 笑え少年よ
Aiya, iyaiya, laugh, young boy!
「ええじゃないか ええじゃないか
"Isn't it fine? Isn't it fine?
この先は何にも分からんし
We don't know what lies ahead anyway.
無礼じゃないか 無礼じゃないか」
Isn't it rude? Isn't it rude?"
クソッタレ 見てられん煩悩
Dammit all, what unwatchable worldly desires!
嗚呼 荒れ狂う世の中だから
Ah, because this world is running wild,
アイアイ アイアイ 宙を舞って 終わりにするの
aiai, aiai, dancing midair to bring it to an end!
ファッションビートで気取って
Strutting to the fashion beat,
チンケな狂人ぶんじゃない
don't play the cheap lunatic.
報われない悲しみ食らってこう
Let's swallow this unrewarded sorrow!
ファッションビートに染まって
Dyed in the fashion beat,
言うことないなら 息しても無駄だ
if you've nothing to say, even breathing is futile.
アイヤ イヤイヤ 笑え少年よ
Aiya, iyaiya, laugh, young boy!
嗚呼 絵に描いたようなストーリー
Ah, a story just like a painting,
僕の色を塗れぬほどに落ちぶれた
fallen so low I can't even paint my own color.
モノクロに尽きる日は ああ
These days ending in monochrome, ah...
乗り越えられたら
if only I could overcome them.
嗚呼 今夜は笑って
Ah, laugh tonight,
あの幽列車にキスをして
and kiss that ghost train,
七色に生まれ変わるのさ
and be reborn in seven colors!
ファッションビートに染まって
Dyed in the fashion beat,
言うことないなら 息しても無駄だ
if you've nothing to say, even breathing is futile.
アイヤ イヤイヤ 笑え少年よ
Aiya, iyaiya, laugh, young boy!
うわー！
Whoa!
楽しー！
That was so fun!
うわー、やっぱ歌って踊るの楽しー！
Whoa, singing and dancing really is so fun!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
いや、さっきちょっとぶつかっちゃったんですけど...
Though, I bumped into you guys a bit earlier...
すんません。
Sorry about that.
え、なんかダンスとかやってたんですか？
Wait, were you doing dance or something?
え？
Huh?
お？
Oh?
なん、なんちゅうか...
Like, how should I put it...
え、なんか撮ってますやん？
Wait, aren't you filming?
え、なんか撮ってますよね？
Um, you're definitely filming, right?
え、っていうか、これ配信... これ配信されてます、これ？
Wait, I mean, is this stream... Is this being livestreamed right now?
え？
What?
ちょっ、著作権とかあるんですけど、初っ端にも！
Wait, there are copyright things, like with that first song too!
え？ちょっと...
Wait, hold on...
なんかコメントがすごい流れてるんですけど
The comments are scrolling by so fast, but...
反転してて読めまちぇん！
They're mirrored, so I can't read them!
えっとなんか、パチパチっつって拍手してくれてつて
Umm, it looks like everyone's clapping like "clap clap,"
なんか「カッコよちょぎ」って何や？
and what does "too cool" even mean?
えっと、あれか... え？草、草... なんか草生やされちゃった。
Uh, is that... huh? "Lol lol"... They're spamming "lol" at me!
で、なんか... ありがとうございます！
And, well... thank you so much!
え、ハッシュタグ「＃轟はじめ生誕祭2024」で
Under the hashtag "#TodorokiHajimeBirthday2024,"
なんかたくさんポストしてくれてるみたいなんですけど
it looks like you've made a ton of posts for me!
なんやろ、このタグは？
What is this hashtag though?
分かんないけど
I don't really know, but...
はじめ祝ってもらってるっちポストしてもらったら嬉しかもん！
if people are posting to celebrate Hajime, I'm super happy!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
え、で、はじめ歌ったり踊ったりとかするのが好きで
So, Hajime loves singing and dancing and stuff,
本当はこうたくさんの人の前でパフォーマンスすることに憧れてて
and I've always dreamed of performing in front of lots of people.
ちょっと上京したいなとか思ってるんですけど
I've been thinking I'd like to move to Tokyo,
ちょっと勇気が出なくて...
but I couldn't quite build up the courage...
はじめなら大丈夫？
Hajime will be fine?
いける？
I can do it?
コメントの方はちょっとどう思ってる？
What do you guys in the chat think?
「可愛い」なんて... あれ？
"Cute"? Wait, huh?
あ、「ダンスうま」！すごい褒められてる！
Ah, "Great dancer"! I'm getting so praised!
あ、「カッコいい」！あ、褒められてる！
Ah, "Cool"! Ah, they're praising me!
よし！じゃあ皆さんにすごい勇気をもらったので、はじめ、
Alright! You've given me so much courage, so Hajime...
行ってきます！
is heading out!
夢を目指して、上京してくる！
I'm going to Tokyo to chase my dream!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
荒れ狂う季節の中を 二人は一人きり さらり
Through the raging season, the two of us are all alone, breezily
明け行く夕日の中を 今夜も昼下がり さらり
Through the dawning sunset, tonight feels like early afternoon, casually
どれほど朽ち果てようと 最後にゃ笑いたい
No matter how much I decay, I want to laugh in the end
何のために戦おうとも 動機は愛がいい ああ
Whatever I may fight for, I'd rather the motive be love, ah...
新しい日々は 探さずとも常に ここに
Brand new days, even without searching, are always here
色々見てきたけれど この瞳は永遠に きらり
I've seen so many things, but these eyes will shine forever, brilliantly
あれほど生きてきたけど 全ては夢みたい
I've lived that long, yet everything feels like a dream
あれもこれも魅力的 でも私は君がいい ああ
This and that are all attractive, but I still prefer you, ah...
どこにいたの 探してたよ
Where were you? I've been looking for you
連れてって 連れてって
Take me along, take me away
何もかも 捨ててくよ
I'll leave everything behind
どこまでも どこまでも
To wherever, to the ends of the earth
荒れ狂う季節の中も 群衆の中も
Through the raging season, through the crowds
君とならば さらり さらり
With you, it's so smooth and breezy
新しい日々も 拙い過去も 全てがきらり
Brand new days and clumsy past, everything shines brightly
無くしてしまったものを 振り返って ほろり
Looking back on what I lost, tears gently fall
時には途方に暮れて ただ風に吹かれて ゆらり
Sometimes at a total loss, just swaying in the wind
息せき切ってきたの
Did you come running out of breath?
行き先は決めたの
Have you decided where to go?
迷わずに行きたいけど 保証はしないよ
I want to go without hesitating, but I make no promises
何か分かったようで
It feels like I understood something,
何も分かってなくて
yet I understood nothing at all,
だけどそれが分かって 本当に良かった
but I'm truly glad that I realized that much.
新しい日々は 探さずとも常に
Even without searching for new days,
ここにある ここに ここに
they're always right here, right here, right here.
色々見てきたけれど この瞳は
Though I've seen all sorts of things, these eyes
永遠に濁らない 永遠に きらり
will never be clouded, shining forever and ever.
生きてきたけど 全ては夢みたい
I've lived my life, but it all feels like a dream.
あれもこれも魅力的でも
Though this and that are both so tempting,
私は君がいい
you're the one I want.
ああ...
Ah...
どこに行っちゃったの 探してたよ
Where did you go? I was looking for you.
連れてって 連れてって
Take me along, take me along.
何もかも捨ててくよ
I'll leave everything behind.
どこまでも どこまでも
Wherever you go, to the ends of the earth.
荒れ狂う季節の中も 群衆の中も
Through raging seasons and through the crowds,
君とならば さらり さらり
with you, it's smooth and effortless.
新しい日々も 拙い過去も
The new days and the clumsy past,
全てがきらり
everything sparkles brightly.
welcome to our シアター
Welcome to our theater.
ほら 踊れば 幕開けの合図が it’s calling you back
Come on, once you dance, the opening cue is calling you back.
月火から水木にお疲れ everybody clap your hands
Good work from Mon-Tue to Wed-Thu, everybody clap your hands!
待ちわびた金土日さ come and bring all your friends
It's the long-awaited Fri-Sat-Sun, come and bring all your friends!
世間はwork, work 目線はdon’t stop
The world goes work, work, don't stop looking ahead.
心も体もボロボロです
My mind and body are completely worn out.
頑張り屋な日本人に everybody clap your hands
To all the hardworking Japanese people, everybody clap your hands!
やるせない朝に うんざりしちゃって
Sick and tired of these gloomy mornings,
何も変わんないroutine 染み込んだ癖
trapped in an unchanging routine and ingrained habits.
ミステイクまた自分のせいに 憧れ持ったの能天気
Blaming myself for mistakes again, daydreaming like a fool—
結局はいつも通りだ
in the end, it's just the same as always.
過ぎ去っていく day by day
Passing by day by day,
考えたって don't know if it's the right way
even if I ponder, I don't know if it's the right way.
吹く風も味方にして let's ride away
Let's make the blowing wind our ally and ride away.
welcome to our シアター
Welcome to our theater.
ほら 踊れば 幕開けの合図が it’s calling you back
Come on, once you dance, the opening cue is calling you back.
波瀾万丈な人生くらいが丁度いいのさ
A turbulent, rollercoaster life is just about right!
君が創るショータイムを
Show us the showtime you create,
見せて 見せて ちょうだい
show me, show me, come on!
Oh yeah
春夏すぎ秋冬に やれやれ everybody clap your hands
Spring and summer pass into fall and winter, good grief, everybody clap your hands!
ギリギリ駆け込んで 間に合うかの never ending game
Rushing in at the last second, will I make it? A never-ending game!
気持ちはgo, go されどもno, no 現実はそう甘くないね
Spirit says go, go, but it's a no, no; reality isn't that sweet, huh?
働き屋な日本人に everybody clap your hands
To all the hardworking Japanese people, everybody clap your hands!
お決まりのsuit and tie how can I be myself and I
The usual suit and tie, how can I be myself and I?
どれもこれも色のない世界には興味ない
I have zero interest in a colorless world where everything looks the same.
見る向こう側で we're gonna find a way
On the other side of what we see, we're gonna find a way!
welcome to our シアター
Welcome to our theater.
ほら 踊れば 幕開けの合図が it’s calling you back
Come on, once you dance, the opening cue is calling you back.
波瀾万丈な人生くらいが丁度いいのさ
A turbulent, rollercoaster life is just about right!
君が創るショータイムを見せて 見せて
Show us, show us the showtime you create!
過ぎ去っていく day by day
Passing by day by day,
考えたって don't know if it's the right way
even if I ponder, I don't know if it's the right way.
吹く風も味方にして let's ride away
Let's make the blowing wind our ally and ride away.
welcome to our シアター
Welcome to our theater.
ほら 踊れば 幕開けの合図が it’s calling you back
Come on, once you dance, the opening cue is calling you back.
波瀾万丈な人生くらいが丁度いいのさ
A turbulent, rollercoaster life is just about right!
君が創るショータイムを見せて 見せて ちょうだい
Show us the showtime you create, show me, show me, come on!
とびっきりショータイム 誰でもショータイム
The ultimate showtime! Showtime for everyone!
あなたのショータイムを見せて頂戴
Please show us your showtime!
とびっきりショータイム 誰でもショータイム
The ultimate showtime! Showtime for everyone!
あなたのショータイムを見せて頂戴
Please show us your showtime!
え、あの、星街すいせいちゃんですよね？
Um, excuse me... you're Hoshimachi Suisei-chan, right?
ご存知かしら？ ありがとう。
Did you know it? Thank you.
え、あの、なんか、急なご縁でしたけど、一緒に歌えて嬉しかったでしょう？
Um, well, it was a sudden turn of events, but you were happy to sing together, right?
私も嬉しかったわ。
I was happy too.
ほら嬉しかった！
See, you were happy!
楽しかった、ありがとう。
It was fun, thank you.
え、でも、でもあの、このシアター勝手に入っていいんですか？
Um, but wait, was it okay to just walk into this theater on our own?
まあ、ダメかもしれないわ。
Well, maybe we weren't supposed to.
ダメなの！？ / うん。
We weren't!? / Yeah.
え、じゃ、怒られるってこと？
Wait, so we're gonna get scolded?
まあ怒られるわ。
Well, we'll get scolded.
なんでここ連れて来てくれたんですか！？
Why did you bring me here then!?
あそこの人がもう銃構えてるわ、こうやって。
That person over there is already aiming a gun like this.
怖っ！怖っ！え、そんな物騒なものですか！？
Scary! Scary! Wait, is it that dangerous!?
あ、違うんです、あの、この人はオーディション出場者で！
Ah, no, wait, this person is an audition contestant!
え！？ / ここ、オーディションやってるんで。
What!? / They're holding auditions here.
オーディション？ / オーディション出場者ってことにしましょ。
Auditions? / Let's just say you're an audition contestant.
なんてこった！ / そうしましょ。
Oh, come on! / Let's go with that.
ここでオーディションやってたんだ…
So they were holding auditions here...
そうだよ。受けたほうがいいんじゃない？ね。
That's right. Shouldn't you audition? Right?
立ち位置…
Mark my spot...
じゃないと撃たれる、撃たれる。 / 怖い、怖いよ！
Otherwise you'll get shot, you'll get shot. / That's scary, so scary!
撃たれるよ、ね。
You'll get shot, you know.
あれ、星街すいせいじゃない！？
Wait, isn't that Hoshimachi Suisei!?
あれ？あれ？あ…あれ？
Huh? Wait... huh?
行けない！じゃあねー！
Oh no! Gotta go, bye!
ええー！？ちょっ、ちょっとやばい！ええー！？
Eeek!? Wait, this is bad! Eeek!?
ありゃ…ええ…
Oh man... uh...
どっちや…
Which way...?
はぁ…
*sigh*
シーッ…
Shh...
[ステップはお静かに / 作詞: Lily Mizusaki / 作曲: mARUTA mANABU]
[Steps in Silence / Lyrics: Lily Mizusaki / Music: mARUTA mANABU]
Step light 奪い取りの Forty forty gem
Step light, grabbing the forty forty gems
抜き足 差し足 荒いくせも武器でしょ
Sneaking steps, stealing steps, even rough habits are your weapon, right?
Step step stepping night 教えるわ
Step, step, stepping night, I'll teach you
その場その場の 思うがままの 殺陣
Stage combat on the fly, just as you please
強気の火蓋 隠して
Hiding the bold sparks of battle
そして 忍びつつ笑って
And smiling while staying stealthy
上品 まかり通る
Elegance prevails
華麗な劇 静かに ちょっと豪快ダンサー
In this splendid play, quiet yet slightly grand dancers
仕留めてあげるわ
I'll finish you off
Step light 同じダンス ばっかじゃダメ
Step light, doing the same dance over and over won't do
Spin out もうひとりの 自分に勝つの
Spin out, overcome the other self inside you
だって 盗まれたら 取り返すのが基本でしょ
After all, if it's stolen, taking it back is the basic rule, right?
歩幅 崩さず 爪先合わせて
Keep your stride steady, aligning your toes
ひらりと かわして 目の前の罠
Nimbly dodge the trap right in front of you
さらりと 手には 証拠と チャンス
Smoothly in hand, the evidence and chance
派手にもう一撃
One more flashy strike
静かに ちょっと豪快ダンサー
Quiet yet slightly grand dancers
仕留めてあげるわ
I'll finish you off
Step light 奪い返し Forty forty gem
Step light, reclaiming the forty forty gems
抜き足 差し足 荒いくせも武器でしょ
Sneaking steps, stealing steps, even rough habits are your weapon, right?
Step step stepping night そのまま踊るのよ
Step, step, stepping night, just keep dancing
嘘ついてちゃダメ
You can't be lying
踏み出してみなよ
Try taking a step forward
ここで 決めるの
Make your decision here
誰も 奪いやしないわ
No one will steal them away
胸に 秘めてる 宝石と
The gems hidden in your chest
静かに踊ろうさ
Let's dance quietly
静かに踊ってよ
Dance quietly
ステップはお静かに
Keep your steps quiet
[Dressing Room A]
[BAD HATTER / 作詞: 中路もとの / 作曲: DYES IWASAKI]
[BAD HATTER / Lyrics: Motono Nakaji / Music: DYES IWASAKI]
sweetie night に mary jane
Mary Jane in the sweetie night
かかと カンカン tap する 伽藍堂
Heels tapping clang-clang in the empty hall
secret sign ほら ご招待
A secret sign, look, you're invited
洒落た帽子とステッキでナビゲート
Navigating with a stylish hat and cane,
Step inside, gonna lunatic すでに狂宴 主催 蓄積した thoughts
Step inside, gonna lunatic; already hosting a feast of accumulated thoughts.
さあ乾杯してBeverage 今はこの欲望に溺れよ
So cheers with a beverage, and drown in this desire for now.
有限なら夜が明ける前まで
If time is limited, until dawn breaks,
味わい尽くすべき
you should savor it to the fullest.
You are BAD HATTER 支配なる Monster
You are BAD HATTER, a dominating monster.
We are BAD HATTER 目線も退場もナンセンス
We are BAD HATTER, glances and exits are all nonsense.
バンバン Moonlight 渋滞のダンスフロア
Bang bang, moonlight, a crowded dance floor.
We are stakeholder 狂騒に呑まれ踊れ
We are stakeholders; be swallowed by frenzy and dance!
バッテン slash to a reaction つまり空中飛び交うキンキンドー
A cross slash to a reaction, glasses clinking across the air.
会場内なら平等さ 老いも若きもバカしか集い合う
Inside the venue, everyone's equal; old and young, fools just gathering together.
Step inside, gonna lunatic 誰も彼もが耳打ち clash talk
Step inside, gonna lunatic; everyone whispering clash talk.
「一緒にどうです？お嬢さん」 素性の怪しい紳士が Shall we dance?
"How about joining me, miss?" A suspicious gentleman asks, "Shall we dance?"
幽霊とかどんな見た目だろうが
Whether they're a ghost or whatever they look like,
気にする暇もない
there's no time to care.
You are BAD HATTER 支配なる Monster
You are BAD HATTER, a dominating monster.
We are BAD HATTER 目線も退場もナンセンス
We are BAD HATTER, glances and exits are all nonsense.
バンバン Moonlight 渋滞のダンスフロア
Bang bang, moonlight, a crowded dance floor.
We are stakeholder 狂騒に呑まれ踊れ
We are stakeholders; be swallowed by frenzy and dance!
ダバドゥバダビディディディルダ ディビディビドゥドゥルジェチェチェルズ
Daba duba dabi didi didi ru da, dibi dibi du duru je che che ruzu
ドゥビダバドゥキャダドゥタラドゥバダビディタールタディビデルー
Dubi daba du kyada du tara duba dabi di taaru ta dibideruu
ダビダビダビダビダビダビダンタラチャビダビダビダビダビダビバラドゥ
Dabi dabi dabi dabi dabi dabi dan tara chabi dabi dabi dabi dabi dabi bara duu
アイバリトゥタラドゥタラティバジャバリタールタディビディバビデドゥー
Aibari tutara dutara tiba jabari taaru ta dibidi babideduu
You are BAD HATTER 支配なる Monster
You are BAD HATTER, a dominating monster.
We are BAD HATTER 目線も退場もナンセンス
We are BAD HATTER, glances and exits are all nonsense.
バンバン Moonlight 渋滞のダンスフロア
Bang bang, moonlight, a crowded dance floor.
We are stakeholder 狂騒に呑まれ踊れ
We are stakeholders; be swallowed by frenzy and dance!
うわっ！お前、チャッキーの奴！何持っちゃーの？
Whoa! You're that Chucky guy! What are you holding?
うわ、バツ?!
Whoa, an X?!
バツってどういうことじゃ？お前な、持ち帰…俺ちゃんの審査員だったの？！
What do you mean, an X?! Wait, you... were you judging my performance?!
ちょ、だってチャッキー、なんかノリノリでドゥビドゥバドゥバダ、チャチャドゥーってやってたじゃん！
Wait, but Chucky, you were totally getting into it, going "doobi dooba dooba da, cha cha doo"!
おい！出てっちゃった！なんだよ！一応頑張っちゃ…
Hey! She left! What the heck! I worked hard on that...
ちょ、ちょっと、ちょっとエッジ効いた…なあ？
A-a little, that was a little edgy... right?
あれ？なんか…だっ、ちゃっちゃっ…動かないんだけど！
Huh? Wait... wha- ch-ch- I can't move!
んんんーっ…！
Mmph... ngh...!
あ、なんか話しかけてもダメみたいだ。
Ah, looks like talking to her won't work.
なんだよ！こっちから願い下げだ！こんな、こんなシアター、出てってやるー！
Whatever! I didn't want to be here anyway! I'm getting out of a theater like this!
へへっ
Heheh!
はぁ…はぁ…
*Panting*
チクショー、あいつ…調子こきやがってよぉ！
Damn it, that jerk... getting so cocky!
何見てんだよ！
What are you looking at?!
はぁ…見てなかった。チェッ！
*Sigh*... They weren't even looking. Tsk!
うっ…ううっ…くそっ！
Ugh... ugh... Damn it!
no thank you alright?
脳天気どうかしている 不適切 指摘には低姿勢で
Carefree and losing our minds; taking criticism of inappropriateness with a low bow.
正義し放題 mr. x 放火している ※真偽不明なんて正気じゃない
Acting self-righteous, Mr. X is setting fires; labeling it *Unverified* is pure insanity.
夜は on and on and on
Night goes on and on and on,
僕ら怨念飲んでへべれけじゃん
we're dead drunk swallowing all this malice, aren't we?
目には？歯には？簡単だ 吸って吐いてジャッジメント
An eye? A tooth? It's simple: inhale, exhale, judgment.
ようやく今晩無礼講決行 こうです
Tonight we finally drop all formalities, that's how it goes.
皆様ナンセンス 甚だナンセンス
Everyone is nonsense, utterly nonsense.
イキる勿れ 黙れ黙れ
Don't act so cocky; shut up, shut up.
この世はナンセンス 誠に遺憾です
This world is nonsense, truly regrettable.
お気の毒ね 哀れ哀れ仕方ねえ
How unfortunate; pathetic, pathetic, nothing can be done.
ほら精々気張っていってらっしゃい
Go on, try your hardest and have a nice trip.
じゃ閻魔によろしく言っといて
Give my regards to King Enma, then.
be quiet alright?
拡声器セールしている 「名義不明だとしてもまいどあり」
Megaphones on sale: "Thanks for your purchase, even if your name is unknown."
誠にアンコールを
Truly, give me an encore!
まさに宣言通り Dirty 30 night
Exactly as declared, Dirty 30 night.
右も左もドントバイ フズ・ホワイト？ チェックメイト
Left and right, don't buy. Who's white? Checkmate.
ようやく今晩 ブレイク 結構です
Finally tonight, a break—no thank you.
皆様 ナンセンス 甚だナンセンス
Everyone, it's nonsense, utterly nonsense!
気流流れ 黙れ 黙れ 黙れ
Go with the airflow—shut up, shut up, shut up!
この世はナンセンス 誠に感謝です
This world is nonsense, truly thank you very much!
気の毒ね 哀れ 哀れ 哀れ
How pitiful—how pathetic, pathetic, pathetic!
1, 2, Understand?
Yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
Yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
皆様 ナンセンス 甚だナンセンス
Everyone, it's nonsense, utterly nonsense!
気流流れ 黙れ 黙れ
Go with the airflow—shut up, shut up!
この世はナンセンス 初めからナンセンス
This world is nonsense, nonsense from the start!
気流流れ 黙れ 黙れ 黙れ
Go with the airflow—shut up, shut up, shut up!
間もなく時間です 誠に感謝です
It's almost time, truly thank you very much!
置き忘すんな 去れ 去れ くたばれ
Don't leave things behind—leave, leave, drop dead!
ほら 成績ばっか言ってた奴は 退場しちゃっていいから
Look, whoever kept talking about grades can just leave.
Rest in peaceでごめんなさい
Sorry, rest in peace!
嘘つきに仰せ、仰せ... I'll see you again!
To the liar, as you say, say, say... I'll see you again!
わあ！どこ行ってた？危にゃ！危ないんじゃないですかー！
Whoa! Where were you going? Watch out! Isn't that dangerous?!
ん？何その動き。お前、ダンサーか？
Huh? What's with those moves? Are you a dancer?
え？ダンサーですけど。
Huh? Yes, I'm a dancer, though.
私たちもダンサーでーす！
We're dancers too!
え、なんかすごいダンサーがいっぱい出てきた。
Whoa, a bunch of amazing dancers just showed up!
え、なんかさ、はじめさっきダンスのオーディション落ちちゃってさ…
Uh, the thing is, I just failed a dance audition earlier...
もしかして、あそこの審査員ですか？
Could it be those judges over there?
え、それ私も落ちました！
Huh? I failed that too!
えー！私も！私も！みんな落ちた仲間？！
What?! Me too! Me too! We're all failed audition buddies?!
ねえ、あのミニ番長審査員、センスねえよな！
Hey, that mini-gang-leader judge has zero sense, right?!
ほんとそれ！センスない！
Totally! No sense at all!
いやいやいや、ウチらのダンスをちゃんと見せつけてやろうじゃ！
No, no, no, let's show them what our dancing is really made of!
おー！
Yeah!
もう壁とは踊らないぞ！一閃、梨々華！
I'm not dancing with walls anymore! In a flash, Ririka!
3メートルの覇気、こぼ・かなえるー！
3 meters of ambition, Kobo Kanaeru!
カオスに堕ちる、ハコス・ベールズ！
Falling into chaos, Hakos Baelz!
宇宙一の番長になる、轟はじめ！
Set to be the universe's #1 gang leader, Todoroki Hajime!
よーし、ウチらの始まりは…
All right, our beginning is...
こっからーーー！
Right from here!
こっから
[Song: Kokkara]
平凡、平凡にBorn、だに晩 産声「オギャー」 行く先は荒野
Mediocre, born into mediocrity, cries at night "Waaah!", bound for the wilderness.
呑まれた奴がいかにして勝つか 深く眠る米が掘れますか？
How does the swallowed one win? Can you dig up the deep-sleeping talent?
知るか、乗るか、反るか、しかめ面 夜毎の中 確かな価値観のドブ勝つかと
Who knows, sink or swim, frowning, in every passing night, can solid values conquer the gutter?
なんだってこの葛藤で生まれた Take 格闘で生きよう
Whatever it is, take what was born from this conflict, and live by fighting!
I can't be someone else, so I know I know
このブレイクを壊したいの？ 才能？
Do you want to break this break? Talent?
これだけじゃやれねえって分かってる でもこれしかねえからこれにかかってる
I know I can't make it with just this, but this is all I got so I'm banking on it.
間違ってる未来でも俺には光ってる Let it fire
Even if it's a mistaken future, to me it shines—let it fire!
燃やすこの闘志 その点少し ぶち壊す都市 仕様のないままの自分なんだ
Igniting this fighting spirit, a point a bit, wrecking the city, being just the hopeless self I am.
こっから始まんだ (始まんだ)
It begins from here! (It begins!)
いつかの童心持って努力し 夢通しそう ありのままになれるはずなんだ
Holding onto that childhood wonder, striving through dreams, surely I can become my true self.
こっから こっから始まんだ
From here, it begins from here!
1 2 3 4 順番通り 生きてないだけで予定通り
1 2 3 4, just not living in order, yet right on schedule.
Rolling, rolling, 転がってけ 色とりどりの衣装
Rolling, rolling, keep on rolling, colorful costumes!
1 2 3 4 順番通り 行ってないだけで予定通り
1 2 3 4, just not following the order, yet right on schedule.
Rolling, rolling, 転がってけよ こっから始ま…
Rolling, rolling, keep on rolling, it begins from here...
え、こっから？どっから？分からん だって燃料切ればすっからかん
Eh, from here? From where? I don't know, 'cause if fuel runs out, I'm bone dry.
悲観は楽観視感 旦那、まさに難関
Pessimism is visual optimism, mister, it's truly a tough hurdle.
一人になりたくても人だらけ されど気立つ人も黒の群れ
Even wanting to be alone, it's full of people, yet those who stand out are a crowd in black.
手をこれtake 馴らされpeople でもどこ行ったって people, people, people!
Hands like this, take, tamed people, but wherever you go, people, people, people!
黄色の信号 ずっと進行 死亡した先はあるレッドカーペット
Yellow traffic light, kept moving forward, what lies beyond death is a red carpet!
何何何だった？Come on! よりどりみどりってさっき言ったろ？
What, what, what was that? Come on! Didn't I just say "take your pick"?
嗚呼、有象無象 心のあざ笑う 生きた証がサイタのヒラクだけ？
Ah, the rabble sneering in my heart, is living proof just blooms opening?
しかし悔しさで黒く燃える腹の底 燃やせ！燃やせ！燃やせ！燃やせ！
But burning black with frustration deep in my gut, burn it! Burn it! Burn it! Burn it!
燃やすこの闘志 その点少し ぶち壊す都市 仕様のないままの自分なんだ
Igniting this fighting spirit, a point a bit, wrecking the city, being just the hopeless self I am.
こっから始まんだ (始まんだ)
It begins from here! (It begins!)
いつかの童心持って努力し 夢通しそう ありのままになれるはずなんだ
Holding onto that childhood wonder, striving through dreams, surely I can become my true self.
こっから こっから始まんだ
From here, it begins from here!
1, 2, 3, let's go!
Take it to the bridge
俺 悪くない 何も間違ってない
I'm not in the wrong, I haven't made any mistakes.
自分じゃない何かのせいにしたい
I just want to blame it on anything but myself.
天才じゃないの達観 世話なさいたこれ
Gave up 'cause I'm no genius, look at what a mess I am.
フィクションじゃない よく見なさい
This is no fiction, take a good, hard look.
天賦の才などない でも止められない微罪
No natural talent, but I can't stop this petty crime.
あーアホか馬鹿みたい 弁解
Ah, making excuses like a complete idiot.
こっから 燃える未来 (メラメラ)
From here on, a burning future (blazing up)!
まだまだ 自分で決めつけんな限界
Don't go deciding your own limits just yet!
咲かせお前だけの世界 本当の自分なんて居やしねえよ
Make your own world blossom, your "true self" never existed anyway!
なきゃダメ (ダメ) 聞く言葉 (ダメ) 思い込んでることこそが (ダメ)
"Gotta have it" (Nope!) "Words you hear" (Nope!) "Being convinced is what's..." (Nope!)
好きこそものの上手なれ
What you love, you'll become good at.
継続こそ終える根比べ
Perseverance is an endurance match till the end.
I can be someone else, oh, I know, I know
そのブレイク ぶっ壊したいの したいの
That brake, I wanna smash it, wanna smash it!
明日の我が威張らずに動け
Move forward tomorrow without acting all haughty!
道無き道ほど進め 騙した嫉妬も嫉妬なら燃料
Pave the way where there is no path, if it's jealousy, let it be fuel!
Ready, fire!
燃やすこの闘志 その鉄格子 ぶち壊し
Igniting this fighting spirit, smashing through these iron bars,
どうしようもない馬鹿が自分なんだ 限界突破 こっから始まんだ
A hopeless fool is what I am, breaking limits, it starts from here!
いつかの闘志持って努力し 夢と添い寝し そう兄になれるはずなんだ
Working hard with fighting spirit, sleeping beside dreams, I can make it big!
限界突破 こっから こっから始まんだ
Breaking limits, from here, it all starts from here!
1 2 3 4 順番通り 行かないだけで予定通り
1 2 3 4 In order, things not going as planned IS the plan!
ローリンローリン 転がってけ 思い通り 緑と一緒
Rolling, rolling, keep on rolling, just as you want, along with the greenery!
1 2 3 4 順番通り 行かないだけで大正解
1 2 3 4 In order, things not going in order is totally right!
ローリンローリン 転がってけ
Rolling, rolling, keep on rolling!
こっから始まんだー！
It all starts from here!
数年後
[A few years later]
Ha-ah, ha-ah... Ha-ah, ha-ah...
I can't see what's behind those eyes
Just wait, talk a little before they're right
誰かの理想像に 耳を傾けてしまったの
Did I end up listening to someone else's ideal image?
I can't take it back no more, I guess it's too late to call it off
感情の無い世界に溺れてさ
Drowning in an emotionless world...
Tell me who I'm supposed to be, I'm lost without your honesty
I'm stuck between yes and no, no, no
Don't let me down
This is what you came for 狂ったように舞いな 舞いな
This is what you came for, dance like crazy, dance on
Ha-ah, ha-ah...
Said you wanna be a superstar, yeah, show me you won't break and fall apart
Take me higher, higher
Ha-ah, ha-ah...
Show me you won't break and fall apart
何かを言おうとして
Trying to say something...
間違い探しのスタート合図
...a signal starting a game of spot-the-mistake.
Why's everybody's eyes on me
慣れてしまうものね 視線の的
You get used to being the center of attention, don't you?
I can't take it back no more, I guess it's too late to call it off
感じるプレッシャーは押し殺してさ
Suppressing the pressure I feel...
Tell me who I'm supposed to be, I'm lost without your honesty
いい子気取りじゃ no, no, no
Playing the good girl won't work, no, no, no
Don't let me down
This is what you came for 狂ったように舞いな 舞いな
This is what you came for, dance like crazy, dance on
Ha-ah, ha-ah...
Said you wanna be a superstar, yeah, show me you won't break and fall apart
Take me higher, higher
Ha-ah, ha-ah...
Show me you won't break and fall apart
Yeah, said you wanna be a superstar, so show me what you got!
I can't take it back no more, I guess it's too late to call it off
感情の無い世界に溺れてさ
Drowning in an emotionless world...
Tell me who I'm supposed to be, I'm lost without your honesty
I'm stuck between yes and no, no, no
Don't let me down
This is what you came for 狂ったように舞いな 舞いな
This is what you came for, dance like crazy, dance on
Ha-ah, ha-ah...
Said you wanna be a superstar, yeah, show me
Forget what about
Ha-ah, ha-ah
Na-na-na, na-na-na, na
Take me higher, higher
Ha-ah, ha-ah
Woo! Yeah!
Show me you won't forget what about
Ha-ah, ha-ah
うわぁ、みなさん、
Wah, everyone...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
仲間と励まし合って、
Encouraging each other with my friends,
みんなから勇気をもらって、
and drawing courage from all of you,
こうしてステージに立って、
being able to stand on stage like this
たくさんの人の前でパフォーマンスすることができました！
and perform in front of so many people!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そして、なんと、Xトレンド1位！
And to top it off, trending #1 on X!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そして、チャンネル登録者様も120万人様にいったみたいで、
Also, it looks like we reached 1.2 million subscribers,
本当にありがとうございます！
so thank you all so very much!
うわぁ、嬉しい。
Wah, I'm so happy.
まあこうしてね、こう夢を追いかけて上京して、
Chasing my dream like this and moving to Tokyo,
こう、たくさんの人のスターになることができました！
I was able to become a star to so many people!
届けはじめ... えーちょ、うわぁ
Starting to reach... wait, whoa!
まあでもね、この物語をお送りするにあたって、
Still, in bringing this story to life,
たくさんの素敵なアーティストさんの楽曲をお借りして、
we were able to borrow songs from many wonderful artists
あの、作ることができましたので、本当にありがとうございます！
to make it happen, so thank you all so very much!
はじめも曲をたくさん作れるように頑張ります！
Hajime will work hard to create lots of songs too!
そして、これがはじめの100万人記念の新衣装になります！
And this is Hajime's new outfit celebrating 1 million subscribers!
衣装の名前はブラックオーダー衣装です！
The outfit is called the "Black Order" outfit!
市原達也さんに仕立てていただきました！
It was designed and tailored by Tatsuya Ichihara-san!
はじめ...
Hajime...
みなちゃんがね、応援してくれたおかげです！ありがとうございます！
It's all thanks to everyone supporting me! Thank you so much!
で、今回の新衣装ね、
So, with this new outfit,
髪がロング！
my hair is long!
そして足がなんか、すごく長く見えるデザインで、
And the design makes my legs look super long,
ほら、セクシーなおみ足！
look, sexy legs!
…で、みなさん、何かお気づきじゃない？
...And everyone, haven't you noticed something?
ぴょこぴょこがない！
The bouncy antennae are gone!
嘘だ！そんなバカな！そんなバカな！ぴょこぴょこがないだと？！
No way! That's impossible! That can't be! No bouncy antennae?!
うわ、嘘です！ぴょこぴょこもあります！うわぁ！
Wah, just kidding! The bouncy antennae are here too! Whoa!
まあぴょこぴょこないと脳みそ出ちゃうからね、必要だよね。
Well, without the bouncy antennae my brain would spill out, so they're necessary.
であと、ジャケットも脱げます！ほら！ほらセクシーや！
And also, I can take off the jacket! Look! See, so sexy!
ほや、詳しくはこのあとのメン限で紹介するので、気になる方は見に来てください！
Anyway, I'll show it off in detail during the members-only stream after this, so please come check it out!
続いてなんと、新曲を披露しようと思います！
Next, I'd like to perform a brand-new song!
みなさん、盛り上がる準備できてますかー？！うぉーい！
Everyone, are you ready to get hyped?! Whoa-oa!
「お団子かわいい」ありがとう！
"Cute buns," thank you!
とてもね、かっこよくて、なんかセクシーな感じの曲になってるので、ぜひ聴いてください！
It's a really cool, kinda sexy song, so please give it a listen!
それでは行きます！『Deep Dive』！
Here we go! "Deep Dive"!
Deep Dive
作詞: Mia Cozy / 作曲: SILLY TEMBA, Mia Cozy / 編曲: SILLY TEMBA
[Song: Deep Dive
Lyrics: Mia Cozy / Music: SILLY TEMBA, Mia Cozy / Arrangement: SILLY TEMBA]
May night 今夜は waste make our rules
May night, tonight let's make our rules
Baby すべて真夜 Let's get party, yeah
Baby, midnight is everything, let's get party, yeah
頭から爪先 決まった looks
From head to toe, perfect looks
Okay my ladies, I need you to show me
Wow マジ gorgeous dance, you look so badass
Wow, truly gorgeous dance, you look so badass
Scream, scream, screaming shout (Hey!)
Wow マジ gorgeous dance, you look so badass
Wow, truly gorgeous dance, you look so badass
Scream, scream, screaming shout (Hey!)
Turn it up now
Me and my girls, me and my girls
見てよ We are amazing, we are so amazing
Look at us, we are amazing, we are so amazing
Me and my girls, me and my girls
ここから dive
From here on, dive
Yeah, so much hypnotic
Dive, let's deep dive
I wanna deep dive
Dive, yeah deep dive (Hey, hey, hey)
Dive, let's deep dive
I wanna deep dive
Dive, yeah deep dive
Let's get it all the turn down
Let's get it all turned down
Dive, you're look like that girl, マジ you're so hot, fine
Dive, you look like that girl, seriously so hot and fine
まさに queen, hot queen, hot queen, yeah
Truly a queen, hot queen, hot queen, yeah
You're look like that girl, マジ you're so hot, fine
You look like that girl, seriously so hot and fine
まさに queen, hot queen, hot queen
Truly a queen, hot queen, hot queen
Monster talk
The stalker law
The metamour
To my hardcore
成り勝つ so shiny
Coming out on top, so shiny
マスカラ敷いた on bunny
Mascara on, a bunny
噛み倒されたもう party
Thoroughly chewed up, now party
Ooh la la, ooh la la (Yeah!)
視線を control (I don't mind that)
Controlling their gaze (I don't mind that)
誰かの vogue (I don't need no more)
Someone's vogue (I don't need no more)
Wow マジ gorgeous dance, you look so badass
Wow, truly gorgeous dance, you look so badass
Scream, scream, screaming shout
Hey!
Turn it up now, make call!
Turn it up now, make a call!
Are you ready? Are you ready? Ready go!
Me and my girls, me and my girls
We gotta we gotta we gotta we gotta we get it
Click-click-click-click-click-click
Crash it, crash it
Let's get back to beat, you saw my Hot Queen
Dive, let's deep dive, I wanna deep dive
Dive, yeah deep dive
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Dive, let's deep dive, I wanna deep dive
Dive, yeah deep dive
Let's get it on, let it burn down
Girl, you look like that girl
マジヤバ 半端 まさに Queen
Insanely crazy, nothing half-hearted, truly a Queen
Hot Queen, Hot Queen
Girl, you look like that girl
マジヤバ 半端 まさに Queen
Insanely crazy, nothing half-hearted, truly a Queen
Hot Queen, Hot Queen
Guns of Saxophone / 作曲: 樋田花亮
[Guns of Saxophone / Composed by Karyo Hida]
はい、ということで！生誕グッズが出ましたー！
All right, so! The birthday merch is finally out!
えー、轟はじめ、誕生日記念2026ということで、
So, for the Todoroki Hajime Birthday Celebration 2026,
フルセットはこんな感じです！
here's what the full set looks like!
ひとつずつ紹介していきまーす！
I'll introduce them one by one!
ひとつ目！ぶんぶんばんちょーアクリルスタンド！
First up! The Bunbun Bancho Acrylic Stand!
イラストは、A5き先生に描いていただきました！
The illustration was drawn by Agoki-sensei!
台座パーツがふたつあるので、
It comes with two base parts,
座ってる風にも、こう乗っかったとしても使えます！
so you can display it sitting down or hooked onto things!
怒ってるのがポイントです！
The angry expression is the best part!
ふたつ目！はじめとおそろいチョーカー！
Second! The Matching Choker with Hajime!
はじめの新衣装とおそろいのチョーカーです！
It's the same choker that matches my new outfit!
星のチャームが可愛い！
The star charm is so cute!
首のサイズが合わないよって方は、カバンなどに付けてください！
If it doesn't fit around your neck, feel free to attach it to your bag!
3つ目！BANCHOジャージ！
Third! The BANCHO Jersey!
裏面のイラストは、おもちチャウダーさんに描いていただきました！
The back illustration was drawn by Omochi Chowder-san!
表目は刺繍になってます！
The front design is embroidered!
スバル先輩の生地がとても良かったので、同じのにしていただきました！
Subaru-senpai's fabric was so nice, so we used the same material!
最後！ぬいぐるみキーホルダー ブラックオーロラ衣装バージョン！
And last! Plush Keychain: Black Aurora Outfit Ver.!
はじめが出した人気のぬいぐるみの新衣装バージョンです！
It's the new outfit version of my popular plushie!
あの時買えなかったよっていう方、ぜひお迎えしてください！
If you couldn't get it back then, please make sure to take one home!
そして、フルセット特典はこちら！
And here is the full set purchase bonus!
今回のライブのチケット風カード！全員に直筆サイン書かせていただきます！
A concert ticket-style card! I'll be hand-signing every single one!
去年のね、ライブでたくさんグッズを買っていただいたおかげで、
Thanks to everyone buying so much merch during last year's live,
今年もこんなに力を入れることができました！ありがとうございます！
we were able to put this much effort into it again this year! Thank you so much!
今回のライブも楽しんでいただけただろうか…
I hope you're all enjoying today's live show too...
ぜひね、グッズをお迎えしていただけると、今後の励みになりまちゅ！
Picking up the merch will really encourage me for what's ahead!
よろしくお願いしまちゅ！
Thank you so much for your support!
以上、グッズ紹介でしたー！
And that concludes the merch showcase!
さあ、みんなー！
All right, everyone!
このあとラストスパート！一緒に盛り上がってってください！いきまちよー！
It's time for the home stretch! Let's get hyped up together! Here we go~!
Hey!
Ow!
イェーイ！フゥー！
Yeah! Woo!
ハイ！
Hi!
ヘイ！ヘイ！
Hey! Hey!
アー！
Ah!
うわぁ！やったぁ！ありがちょ〜！
Woah! We did it! Thank you so much!
はぁ〜、やったー！ありがとうございます！
Whew, we did it! Thank you so much!
それでは今回のライブに携わってくださった方をご紹介していきたいと思います！
Now, I'd like to introduce the people who helped make this live show possible!
まずはダンサー、ゆめにゃ！
First, our dancers: Yumenya!
で、しおでぃあ！
And Shiodia!
うみなみあ！
Uminamia!
そら！
Sora!
ありがとう！そしてこの場にはいないんですけど、
Thank you! And though they're not here right now...
振付師のMiu K-ne. Tsushima先生！
Choreographers: Miu K-ne. Tsushima-sensei!
タップのAYAKA先生！
Tap dance coach: AYAKA-sensei!
で、ポッピン、DODO先生！
Popping coach: DODO-sensei!
ダンスコーチ、YUKA先生！
Dance coach: YUKA-sensei!
ボーカルコーチ、MARIA先生！
Vocal coach: MARIA-sensei!
そしてゲストにお越しいただきました、
And our wonderful guests who joined us:
星街すいせいちゃん、
Hoshimachi Suisei-chan,
ハコス・ベールズちゃん、
Hakos Baelz-chan,
一条莉々華ちゃん、
Ichijou Ririka-chan,
儒烏風亭らでんちゃん、
Juufuutei Raden-chan,
本当にありがとうございます！
thank you all so very much!
そして、今見えない中で稼働してくださってるスタッフの皆ちゃん！
Also, a huge thank you to all the staff working behind the scenes right now!
そしてはじめの目の前にいてくれてる、見てくれた皆様、本当にありがとうございます！
And to everyone right here in front of me and watching online, thank you so much!
それでは、ちょっと新曲について詳しくご紹介したいなと思います！
Now then, I'd like to share a few more details about my new song!
改めてタイトルは、『Deep Dive』！
Once again, the title is "Deep Dive"!
はい！MV公開はこの配信のすぐ後です！
Yes! The music video will premiere right after this stream!
音源リリースは本日24時からになります！
And the digital release will be available today starting at 24:00!
皆さんたくさん聴いていただけると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if everyone gives it lots of listens!
さぁ、それではここで重大発表いきたいと思います！
Alright then, it's time for a major announcement!
こちらの動画をご覧ください！
Please take a look at this video!
轟はじめ × FILA コラボ決定！！
[Title: Todoroki Hajime x FILA Collaboration Confirmed!!]
COMING SOON!!
[Title: COMING SOON!!]
うわぁー！すごい！
Woah! That's awesome!
この度、はじめとFILAちゃんのコラボが決定しましたー！
Hajime and FILA are officially doing a collaboration!
うわぁ嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
Woah, I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
そしてなんと、スニーカーを含むアパレルをプロデュースさせていただきましたー！
And amazingly, I got to produce apparel, including sneakers!
やったー！
Yay!
はじめっぽいカラーリングを取り入れながら、
Incorporating colors inspired by Hajime,
男性でも女性でも似合うように意識してデザインしてみました！
I designed them so they would look great on anyone, regardless of gender!
一足目、はじめのこだわりを詰め込んだスニーカーにしていくので、
This first pair will be packed with my personal touches,
続報を楽しみにしていてください！
so please look forward to more updates!
そして今回なんと、スニーカーだけじゃなくてね、
And that's not all—besides sneakers,
ジャージとTシャツとキャップもプロデュースしましたー！
I also produced track jackets, T-shirts, and caps!
さらにコラボにあたって、オリジナルのコラボロゴをFILAちゃんと作りました！
Furthermore, for this collab, FILA and I created an original collaboration logo!
ドドン！
Ta-da!
うわぁ、可愛い！
Woah, so cute!
実はこのロゴ、FILAちゃんと一緒に打ち合わせをして考えました、はじめ。
Actually, Hajime came up with this logo through brainstorming meetings with FILA!
あ、こういう感じだね。実際にこう手描きをしながら打ち合わせをして、
Ah, just like this! We had meetings while sketching out designs by hand,
どの色がいいかなーって、いろんな色味を出してもらって作りました！
testing out various color swatches to decide on the best look!
一目でね、はじめだってわかる、
Thinking it would be nice to easily recognize it as Hajime at a glance,
こうミニ番長のシルエットがいいかなと思って入れてみました！
I decided to include a silhouette of mini Bancho!
このロゴがね、コラボの商品にも付きます！
This logo will be featured on the collaboration items!
楽しみにしなーい？
Aren't you excited?
実はね、アパレル以外にもFILAちゃんとのコラボ商品が出ますので、
Actually, there will be collab items with FILA besides apparel as well,
皆さん詳細な情報が出るのをぜひお楽しみに、お待ちください！
so please stay tuned and look forward to more details!
この後ですね、メン限でアンコールライブ、21時15分からありますし、
After this, there will be a members-only encore live starting at 21:15,
この新衣装についてTwitterもいろいろ詳しく見ていければと思いますので、
and I'd love to take a closer look at this new outfit on Twitter,
ぜひまだの方はチャンネル登録と通知をオンにして、メン限も入っていただけると、
so if you haven't yet, please subscribe, turn on notifications, and consider joining the membership...
アンコールも一緒に楽しめてハッピーだなと思います！
I'd be so happy to enjoy the encore live together with everyone!
おさらいをすると、
To recap everything:
新曲MV、このあとすぐ公開！
New song MV premiere right after this!
21時からグッズ販売！
Merch sales start at 21:00!
21時15分からアンコールライブ！
Encore live at 21:15!
24時、新曲音源リリースです！
And at 24:00, digital single release!
ありがちょねー！
Thank you all so much!
それでは、メン限アンコールライブでお会いしまちょー！
With that, let's meet up at the members-only encore live!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
いっぱいコメントありがちょー！
Thanks for all the comments!
嬉しかったー！
I was so happy!
ありがとおー
Thank you!